准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
舞会监护人
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
别哭了  亲爱的
Don't cry, love
老爸会处理好的
Daddy's going to make it all right
冷静下来  乖女儿
Calm down, girl
蟹老板  珍珍怎么了
Mr. Krabs, what's wrong with Pearl?
她那个烂舞伴放了她鸽子  小子
Her scurvy prom date stood her up, boy
现在她又没法另外再找一个舞伴
and now she can't seem to find another
因为他是全海洋里唯一
That's because there's only one fish in the sea
又高又帅  肤色又古铜的鱼
as long, tan, and handsome as he is
非他不可
And that's him
不不  宝贝
No, no, baby
别哭了
No more crying
我们会给你找个舞伴的
We'll get you a date
那
Why
我陪你去舞会吧
I'll take you
章鱼哥怎么样
What about Squidward?
等等  等等
Wait, wait
就让海绵宝宝陪吧
Here, take SpongeBob
煎炸厨师
The fry cook?
知道那样会怎么影响我气质吗
Do you know what that would do to my complexion?
别人会把我误认成天文馆的
People will mistake me for a planetarium
你这是什么意思
What do you mean?
不知道
I don't know
可我就是不能带他去  老爸
But I can't take him, daddy
他们会把我踢出
They'll kick me off
年鉴委员会常驻人员的
the most frequently pictured
in the yearbook committee
还真是
Yeah, they would
必须再找个别人
We've got to find someone else
听好了
Listen up
你们当中有哪个幸运儿
Which one of you lucky lubbers
想要陪我可爱女儿珍珍参加舞会
wants to take me lovely daughter pearl to the prom?
别迟到了  海绵宝宝
Just don't be late, SpongeBob
听好了  小子
Now listen, boy
我指望着你把今晚变成
I'm a-counting on you to make this
为特别的女孩打造的特别的夜晚
a very special night for a very special girl
要记住  你这全都是为了蟹
Remember, you're doing it for good old Mr.
蟹老板好
Hi, Mr. Krabs
你是在跟我做的假人说话吗
Are you talking to that dummy I made?
是不是很逼真
It's pretty realistic, isn't it?
这部位的材料是
I made this part out of
别管了  小子
Never mind that, boy
你陪珍珍参加舞会
You're taking Pearl to her prom
真的吗
Really?
你放心  蟹老板
Don't worry, Mr. Krabs
我是舞会专家
I am a prom expert
小蜗  我是舞会废物
Oh, Gary, I'm a prom failure
我连自己的初中舞会都找不到舞伴
I couldn't even get a date for my own junior prom
不对  让妈妈当舞伴的是派大星
No, that was Patrick who brought his mom
并且我又怎么能比得上珍珍的前男友
Besides, how am I supposed to compare with
Pearl's old boyfriend
又高又帅皮肤古铜先生
Mr. Long, tan and handsome?
怎么了  小蜗
What is it, Gary?
你有什么
What do you have?
我说  小蜗
Say, Gary
又高又帅
肤色古铜
这本杂志让我想到办法了
This magazine gives me an idea
高
Long
皮肤古铜
Tan
帅
Handsome
好了小蜗  就等珍珍看到我这身了
Okay, Gary, wait till Pearl gets an eyeful of this
你好
Hello?
你觉得怎么样  珍珍
What do you think, Pearl?
打理得真的还不错  对吧
Cleans up pretty good, doesn't he?
起码没人会认得出你
Well, at least no one will recognize you
听好了  海绵宝宝
Now, listen, SpongeBob
我只想熬过这场舞会
I just want to get through this dance
并且保住我的社交地位
with my social status intact
我想参加舞会  拍完我的照
I want to go to the prom, get my picture taken
我想跳舞  明白吗
and I want to dance, okay?
我想跟朋友一起喝潘趣酒
I wanna drink punch with my friends
也不要做你平常做的其他事情
And don't do that other thing you're always doing
珍珍  得上豪车了
Pearl, we got to get back to the limo
豪车
A limo
你怎么不早说
Why didn't you say so?
我好爱豪车
I love limousines
对他宽容点  小妹
Go easy on him, lassie
我可没钱再另外请个煎炸厨师
I can't afford to break in a new fry cook
体育馆  舞会之夜
这体育馆看着真是好
The gym looks wonderful
出口
我们应该做的第一件事就是
Well, I guess the first thing we should do is
我的第一张舞会照
My first prom picture
我们的第一张舞会照
Our first prom picture
把事先成了吧
Let's get this over with
过来吧  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
马上到
Be right there
你能不能快点
Will you hurry up?
等一下
Just a second
来了
Coming
对不起
Sorry
我来了
Here I am
茄子
Cheese
值得留作纪念
That will be a keeper
快看  是珍珍
Look, it's Pearl
嗨  珍珍
Hi, Pearl
海绵宝宝  我朋友来了
SpongeBob, here come my friends
去给我打点潘趣酒
Go get me some punch
舞会专家  出发
Prom expert, away
嗨  珍珍
Hi, Pearl
嗨  姐妹们
Hi, girls
我想带你认识一下比利鱼金
I'd like you to meet Billy Fishkins
认识数学课上的那个比目鱼布莱恩吧
And you know Bryan Flounder from math class
嗨  布莱恩
Hi, Bryan
那么
So
你的舞伴在哪  珍珍
Like, where's your date, Pearl?
我们好想见见他
We're dying to meet him
他在潘趣酒碗那边打潘趣酒
He's over at the punch bowl getting me some punch
是那个高个子吗
Is he the really tall one?
没错
Oh, yes
我是说  不是
I mean, oh, no
快  去看看辛迪的裙子有多丑
Quick, let's go see how ugly Cindy's dress is
谢谢
Thank you
好  谢谢
Yeah, thanks
海绵宝宝  你在干什么
SpongeBob, what are you doing?
嗨  珍珍
Hi, Pearl
来吧  不会有事的
Come on, it won't bite
你样子太可笑了
You look ridiculous
怎么了
What is it?
快蹲下  我们会被看到的
Get down, they'll see us
是我的前男友  屋大维霸王
It's my ex-boyfriend, Octavius Rex
又名又高又帅皮肤古铜
aka Long, tan and handsome
不过他肯定保不住
But I bet he isn't holder
地方浪漫舞大赛奖杯
of the regional romantic dance championship trophy
快还给我
Give me that back
刚刚没事
That didn't just happen
走吧
Let's go
好了吗
Ready?
海绵宝宝  你在干什么
SpongeBob, what are you doing?
看不出来大家都在跳碰撞舞吗
Can't you see everybody here is doing the whack?
碰撞舞
The whack?
没错  是我发明的
Oh, yeah, I invented that one
你确定你会跳吗
Are you sure you can do this?
我的腿
My leg
看来你可以带我回家了
Well, I guess you can take me home now
现在你全都搞砸了
Now that you've ruined everything
别哭  有舞会专家在
Don't cry, the prom expert is here
我从来没弄砸过
I haven't failed yet
我们还能
We can still
不  我弄坏了
No, I broke that
有了
I know
我们能
We could
不
No
别哭  别哭
Don't cry, don't cry
不管做什么  别
Whatever you do, don't
你对他做了什么
What did you do to him?
可怜的小家伙
Poor little guy
海绵宝宝  没事吧
Sponge, are you okay?
全搞砸了
Ruined everything
别担心了  海绵宝宝
Don't worry, SpongeBob--
你并没有完全搞砸啊
You didn't mess everything up
热狗
Hot dog
其实热狗掉朱迪头发上
Actually, it was pretty funny
真的还挺好笑的
when that hot dog landed in Judy's hair
我只要你玩得开心而已
All I wanted was to have a good time
可我的确玩得很开心啊
But I am having a good time
要知道咱们舞还没跳完呢
You know, we haven't finished our dance yet
我还能戴假发吗
Can I still wear the wig?
好  你还是可以戴假发
Yes, you can still wear the wig
走吧
Let's go
舞曲
好了  各位无脊椎动物
All right, you invertebrates
我要教你们怎么跳海绵舞
I'm going to teach you how to do the sponge
快把腿抬起来
Well, if you take your leg
再抬到半空中
and you stick it in the air
再抬起另一条腿
And then you take the other one
然后在那不要动
And jam it right up there
转身转一周
You twist yourself around
然后一顿猛扑
and give a great big lunge
这样就是海绵舞
Now you're doing the sponge
跳海绵舞吧
Huh, do the sponge, sponge
跳海绵舞
Oh, do the sponge
你肯定就在跳海绵舞
Bet your buns you're doing the sponge
你要把腿抬起来
Well, now, first you take your leg
再抬到半空中
And you stick it in the air
再抬起另一条腿
And then you take the other one
然后在那不要动
And you jam it right up there
快滚  披萨顶料
Get lost, pizza topping
没看到我在跳海绵舞吗
Can't you see I'm doing the sponge?
然后一顿猛扑
and give a great big lunge
这样就是
Now you're doing
对  这样就是海绵舞
Yeah, now you're doing the sponge
好了没错
All right now
跳海绵舞吧
Yeah, do the sponge, sponge
跳海绵舞
Oh, do the sponge
不知不觉你就入水了
Before you know, you're taking the plunge
我说海绵舞
I said the sponge, sponge
跳海绵舞
Oh, do the sponge
你肯定就在跳海绵舞
Bet your buns you're doing the sponge
对  你肯定就在跳海绵舞
Yeah, bet your buns you're doing the sponge
没错  这样就是海绵舞
Oh, yeah, well, you're doing the sponge
主队
客队
跳海绵舞吧
Oh, I said the sponge, sponge
进球得分
跳海绵舞
Yeah, do the sponge
跳海绵舞吧
Yeah, do the sponge, sponge
他们爱我们
They love us
我们火了
We're popular
能不能去破坏别人的舞会
Go wreck someone else's prom, will you?
天啊  珍珍
Gee whiz, Pearl
抱歉今晚没照着你的计划走
I'm sorry tonight didn't turn out like you planned
别担心了  海绵宝宝
Don't worry, SpongeBob
我一直都知道今晚会特别烂
I knew it would be a total disaster all along
不过就烂而言  还真的很好玩
But as far as disasters go, that was really fun
离我的宝贝小花远点
Keep away from my precious little flower
你差点就踩到了
You almost stepped on it
老爸
Daddy
晚安  又矮又黄小海绵
Well, goodnight, short, yellow and spongy
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
干得漂亮  小子
Good job, laddie
你在这啊  假人
There you are, dummy
你真的好有用
You sure come in handy
本月最佳员工
分镜总监
分镜
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
嘿  章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
此处点餐
嘿  章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
好  我会咬钩的
Okay, I'll bite
什么事  海绵宝宝
What is it, SpongeBob?
知不知道今天是什么日子
Do you know what today is?
烦死章鱼哥日
Annoy Squidward day?
不对  傻瓜
No, silly
那是15号
That's on the 15th
蟹堡王
今天要开始
Today's the beginning of
本月最佳员工
评本月最佳员工了
the judging for employee of the month
海绵宝宝  知不知道
SpongeBob, don't you know
那个评奖都是骗人的
that award is a scam?
什么意思
What do you mean?
蟹老板给你评那个奖
Mr. Krabs gives you that award
这样就省得再加钱激励你努力工作了
so you'll work harder for no extra money
那样不对  章鱼哥
That is not true, Squidward
他给我评奖就是因为我努力工作
He gives it to me because I work harder
你也可以赢到的  再努力点就行了
You could win it, too, if you tried harder
图什么
For what?
把我脸挂上耻辱墙吗
To get my face on the wall of shame?
月度最佳员工
章鱼哥  你这样是不对的
Squidward, you've got it all wrong
对自己的工作自豪没什么好耻辱的
Having pride in your work is nothing to be ashamed of
只有一个东西能让一切变得值得
Why, it's the only thing that makes it all worthwhile
就是这样  海绵宝宝
Thattaboy, SpongeBob
马上就是一场硬仗了
This is going to be a tough one, though
没有明确的赢家
There's no clear-cut winner
小心点  海绵宝宝
Watch out, SpongeBob--
章鱼哥似乎马上就要迎头赶上了
Squidward appears to be on the verge of a breakout
皱眉文摘
这个月的墙上估计就会有张新面孔了
There might be a new face on the wall this month
一月
没错  海绵宝宝
That's right, SpongeBob
我估计就要追上你了
I might sneak up on you
不
No
我怎么会让工作质量退步这么多
How could I have let the quality of my work slip so much?
需要帮忙吗
Need some help?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
做蟹黄堡
Making Krabby Patties?
你都快失控了
You're losing it
知不知道那个奖项就是堆
Don't you know that award is a load of
垃圾
garbage
求你别把这件事跟蟹老板说
Please, don't tell Mr. Krabs about this
这样会影响到我评奖的机会
It'll hurt my chances of winning the award
已经跟你说过了  那奖项就是堆
I already told you, that award is a bunch of
鬼话
baloney
这话不对  章鱼哥
That is not true, Squidward
跟这顶帽子一样  这奖项代表着
Like this hat, the award is a symbol of
代表着你是个傻子
It's a symbol that you're a chump
不  章鱼哥
No, Squidward
而这个代表着
And this is a symbol of
我对于本月最佳员工奖的看法
what I think of the employee of the month award
一个有经验的本月最佳员工
An experienced employee of the month
总是会在帽子里放铅块
always keeps a brick of lead in his hat
我再跟你说最后一遍
I'm telling you for the last time
这奖项就只是个笑话
that award is nothing but a joke
三月
万一章鱼哥说得对呢
What if Squidward's right?
万一这奖项就是场骗局呢
What if the award is a phony?
这是不是表示
Does this mean
我所有工作都没有意义
my whole body of work is meaningless?
不要再提那种言论  水手
Stow that kind of talk, sailor
现在这是场战争  列兵
This is war now, private
他就是想要你有那么个想法
That's exactly what he wants you to think
我们没时间再胆怯了
This is no time to go lily-livered on us
可是长官
But, sir
战争当中容不下可是  士兵
There's no room for "buts" in war, soldier
他想让你崩溃
He wants you to crack
他在给你耍把戏  看透你的心
He's trying to trick you, get inside your mind
你必须不择手段
You must stop at nothing--
一定要不择手段
and I mean nothing--
击败他
to defeat him
我说得够清楚了吗  列兵
Have I made myself clear, private?
清楚明白  长官
Crystal, sir
好
Good
快出发
Now move out
不能让章鱼哥赢
I won't let Squidward win
要是他起不来  他就上不了班了
He can't go to work if he doesn't wake up
发现目标
Target sighted
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你来这干什么
What are you doing here?
你没法起床上班就评不到奖
You can't win that award if you don't get up for work
住手  海绵宝宝
Stop it, SpongeBob
要是我真的想评奖
If I really wanted that award
就算我爪子被绑起来我也能得
I could win it with my tentacles tied
那就快安排上啊
That can be arranged
你简直是疯了  海绵宝宝
You're a lunatic, SpongeBob
也许是
Maybe so
可我本月最佳员工
but I did win employee of the month
已经连赢26个月了
26 months in a row
你
Are y
你是不是想说你比我强
Are you trying to say that you are better than me?
我已经比你强了26个月了
I've been better than you for 26 months--
明天就是27个月了
and it'll be 27 tomorrow
够了  方块死脑筋
That's it, square-for-brains
够了
That's it
我倒要让你见识见识
I'm going to show you
评上那奖有多简单
how easy it is to win that award
我要当上新的本月最佳员工
I'm going to be the new employee of the month
我会证明给你看
I will prove to you
我能力比你强的多
I am far more competent than you
我很早就到蟹堡王给地板打蜡了
Well, I'm going in early to wax the floors
不用麻烦了
Don't bother
你到的时候我早就打完蜡了
I'll have done it already by the time you get there
那你必须早起才能比我早到蟹堡王
Well, you'll have to get up pretty early
to get there before me
我用不着睡觉
I don't need the sleep
废物
Loser
我也一样
Well, me neither
连输26次的废物
26-time loser
看看他  一直盯着我
Look at him, watching me
我在盯着你呢  海绵宝宝
I'm watching you, SpongeBob
你是不可能比我早走的
You're not leaving before me
章鱼哥  是不是很困呢
Hey, Squidward, getting sleepy, huh?
不困
No
那你呢
How about you?
不困
Nope
晚安
Nighty-night
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
去哪呢
Going somewhere?
等我出去之后我就拧干你
I'm going to wring you dry when I get out of here
快放我出去
Now get me out of here
好  章鱼哥
Okay, Squidward
下班后我会顺便来看看的
I'll stop by after work
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
快去休息休息吧
Now to get some rest
可别一脸劳累地
Don't want to look tired
去拍本月最佳员工照
for my employee of the month photo
章鱼哥
Squidward
这样应该能拖住他
That ought to hold him
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
好你个
Why, you little
失败大废物
蟹黄堡
A Krabby Patty
章鱼哥
Squidward
永别了  海绵大废物
So long, sponge loser
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
休战
Truce
海绵宝宝  我再也受不了了
SpongeBob, I can't take it anymore
要是再这样下去
If we keep this up
我们都会评不到奖的
neither of us will win the award
说得对
You're right
应该要留点力气
We should save our energy for work
做好我们分内的事情
where we really need it
好  那就来场干净的较量
Okay, let's have a good, clean fight
谁能力强谁就能赢
And may the better man win
他就是个谎话连篇毫无骨气
He's nothing but a lying, boneless
又喷墨又鼻子大的大骗子
ink-squirting, big-nosed phony
看看那又露龅牙又俗套的笑容
Look at that buck-toothed, corn-fed smile
他这人可一点都信不得
You can't trust him as far as you can throw him
等到他把我手一握完
As soon as he stops shaking my hand
我就赶快跑
I'm going to make a run for it
蟹堡王
钱  钱
Money, money
要去赚点钱
going to make some money
入口
能看到我员工来这么早
It warms me wallet to see me employees
让我钱包都暖化了
coming in so early
你们来得可真早
Boys, you're early
等等
Wait
蟹老板你看  扫地
Look, Mr. Krabs, clean floors
擦桌子  蟹老板
Clean tables, Mr. Krabs
洗盘子  蟹老板
Clean dishes, Mr. Krabs
这都是怎么了
What's going on here?
这么洗盘子才更高效  蟹老板
It's more efficient to clean dishes this way, Mr. Krabs
不
No
送你的花朵跟巧克力  蟹老板
Flowers and chocolates for you, Mr. Krabs
你看
Look
我把我自己的钱放收银机了  蟹老板
I'm putting my own money into the register, Mr. Krabs
用两把锅铲能提高生产效率  蟹老板
Two spatulas to increase productivity, Mr. Krabs
海绵宝宝  再快点
Faster, SpongeBob, faster
翻肉饼压根不算什么事  蟹老板
There's nothing to this patty flipping, Mr. Krabs
我产量轻轻松松就能到你两倍
I'll easily double your output
海绵小员工
sponge cog
小子
Boys
什么
Wha
救命
Help
免费的蟹黄堡
Free Krabby Patties
看啊  有蟹黄堡
Look at that, Krabby Patties
别走  你们必须要付钱
Wait, you've got to pay for those
别走
Wait
所有人  蟹黄堡
Boys, the Krabby Patties
到底谁评上了本月最佳员工
So who's the winner of employee of the month?
我
Me
别走
Wait
所有人  蟹黄堡
Boys, the Krabby Patties
所有人  等等
Boys, wait